환영한다, 젊은 스카이워커
기다리고 있었다
Welcome,young Skywalker.
I have been expecting you.
You'll no longer need those.
수갑은 필요 없다
Guards, leave us.
경비원은 원위치로!
네 수련을 완성시켜주마
I'm looking forward
to completing your training.
그땐 날 폐하라고 부르겠지
In time, you will call me master.
크게 착각하고 있군
You're gravely mistaken.
You won't convert me
as you did my father.
날 아버지처럼 바꿀 수는 없소
그게 아닐걸, 젊은 제다이
Oh, no, my young Jedi.
착각하고 있는 건 바로 너야
You will find that
it is you who are mistaken...
그것도 아주 많이
about a great many things.
그의 광선검입니다
His lightsaber.
그래, 제다이의 무기로군
Ah, yes. A Jedi's weapon.
네 아버지 것도 이렇게 생겼지
Much like your father's.
너도 곧 아버지 뒤를 따라
암흑 세계에...
By now you must know your father
can never be turned from the dark side.
So will it be with you.
빠져들 거야
You're wrong.
과연 그럴까?
차라리 죽음을 택하겠소
당신과 함께
Soon I'll be dead--
and you with me.
네 일당의 공격이
임박했단 뜻이로군
Perhaps you refer to
the imminent attack of your rebel fleet.
Yes.
여긴 네 생각보다
훨씬 더 안전해
I assure you we are quite safe
from your friends here.
Your overconfidence
is your weakness.
당신의 자만심이
자멸을 초래할 거요
넌 지금 동료들을
과신하고 있어
Your faith in your friends is yours.
더 이상의 저항은
무의미한 일이란다
It is pointless to resist, my son.
모든 것은 내 의도에 따라
지배된다
Everything that has transpired
has done so according to my design.
저 달의 네 친구들은...
Your friends up there
on the sanctuary moon...
지금 덫에 걸려든 거야
are walking into a trap,
as is your rebel fleet.
방어망을 노출시킨 것도
의도적인 일이었지
It was I who allowed the Alliance...
to know the location
of the shield generator.
내가 그렇게 허술한 줄 알았나?
It is quite safe
from your pitiful little band.
An entire legion
of my best troops awaits them.
곧 정예 부대가
그들을 맞이할 거다
네 친구들이 여기에
무사히 도착한다 해도
I'm afraid the deflector shield...
will be quite operational
when your friends arrive.
방어망은 아무 탈 없이
잘만 작동하고 있을 거야
꼼짝 말고 앞장 서!
빨리, 저리로!
All right!
Up! Move!
Quickly. Quickly.
츄이!
Han, hurry.
서둘러요
놈들이 곧 몰려올 거예요
The fleet will be here any moment.
폭탄을 줘, 어서!
Charges. Come on. Come on!
이런, 잡히겠는걸
Oh, my. They'll be captured.
Wait! Come back!
기다려, 돌아와
알투, 같이 있자
R2, stay with me.
멈춰라!
Freeze!
이 멍청한 놈들
You rebel scum.
편대장들은 상황을 보고하라
- All wings report in.
- Red Leader standing by.
적색 편대, 준비 완료
- Gray Leader standing by.
- Green Leader standing by.
회색 편대, 준비 완료
녹색 편대, 준비 완료
공격 태세로 진입 실시
Lock S-foils in attack positions.
포스가 우리와 함께 하길!
May the Force be with us.
We've gotta be able to get
a reading on that shield-- up or down.
레이더에 뭐가 잡히나?
How could they be jamming us
if they don't know--
우리가 도착한 걸 모르잖아?
아무 반응이 없는데
if we're coming.
혹시 정보가...
Break off the attack.
The shield is still up.
공격을 멈춰!
방어망이 안 뚫렸다
I get no reading. You sure?
레이더엔 포착되지 않는다
Pull up! All craft pull up!
다들 멈춰!
공격대형을 풀고
MV-7구역에 가까이 붙어라
Take evasive action. Green Group,
stick close to Holding Sector MV-7.
대장님, 47구역에
적기가 출현했습니다
Admiral, we have
enemy ships in Sector 47.
It's a trap.
함정이다!
적기가 공격해 온다
Fighters coming in.
너무 많다!
There's too many.
Accelerate to attack speed.
Draw their fire away from the cruisers.
최고 속도로 사정권에서 벗어나라
알겠다
Copy, Gold Leader.
이쪽으로 와서 보아라
Come, boy.
See for yourself.
여기서 연합군의 최후와
From here, you will witness
the final destruction of the Alliance...
네 헛된 꿈의 공중분해를
직접 목격하게 되리라
and the end
of your insignificant rebellion.
광선검을 원하고 있군
You want this...
don't you?
The hate is swelling in you now.
이제 네 안에서 증오심이
꿈틀거리기 시작했어
제다이 무기를 사용하거라
Take your Jedi weapon.
Use it.
난 무장해제야, 뭘 하나?
분노를 발산 시키지 않고
I am unarmed.
Strike me down with it.
Give in to your anger.
분노를 발산하는 만큼씩
넌 나의 종이 되어 갈 것이다
With each passing moment
you make yourself more my servant.
싫소!
It is unavoidable.
피할 수 없다
이건 네 운명이니까
It is your destiny.
네 아버지처럼 너도...
You, like your father...
are now...
mine.
내 것이다
어서 움직여라
All right, move it.
안녕하십니까, 여러분?
절 찾고 계시죠?
Hello. I say, over there.
Were you looking for me?
Bring those two down here.
저 놈들을 잡아와
They're on their way.
R2, are you sure this was a good idea?
오고 있다, 알투
이거 정말 잘하는 짓일까?
꼼짝 마!
Freeze.
Don't move.
꼼짝 마라!
We surrender.
항복합니다
암호가 바뀌었어요
The code's changed.
- We need R2.
- Here's the terminal.
-알투가 필요해요
-여기 무전기
알투, 어디 있니?
R2, where are you?
We need you at the bunker
right away.
속히 벙커로 오기 바란다
대체 어딜 가자는 거야?
Going? What do you mean?
어디 가니, 알투?
Going where, R2?
Wait. R2, this is
no time for heroics.
뭐 하는 거야?
영웅이 될 필요는 없어
Come back!
돌아와!
조심해, 위쪽에 세 놈이다
Watch yourself, Wedge.
Three from above.
셋, 둘, 공격!
- Red Three, Red Two, pull in.
- Got it.
알았다
20도 위로 집중 공격
Three of them coming in, 20 degrees.
왼쪽으로!
내가 먼저 간다
Cut left.
I'll take the leader.
놈들이 약품 창고로 간다
They're heading
for the medical frigate.
Pressure's steady.
현상태를 유지하라
지금 공격 중인 편대만 빼곤
모두 대기 중인 것 같은데
Only the fighters are attacking.
What are the Stardestroyers waiting for?
공격 태세 완료입니다
We're in attack position, sir.
기다려
- Hold here.
- We're not going to attack?
왜 공격을 안 합니까?
폐하께서 직접 특명을 내리신다
도망가지만 못하게 해
My orders are from the emperor himself.
He has something special planned.
We only need to
keep them from escaping.
너도 보다시피...
As you can see,
my young apprentice...
your friends have failed.
네 친구들은 오합지졸들이야
이제 이 전투 기지의
Now witness the firepower...
엄청난 위력을 똑똑히 봐라
of this fully armed
and operational battle station.
사령관, 총공격을 개시하라
Fire at will, Commander.
발사!
Fire.
That blast came from the Death Star.
저건 죽음의 별에서
나온 공격이야
공격체계가 작동하잖아?
That thing's operational.
Home 1, this is Gold Leader.
선발대 나와라
우리도 봤다, 모두 후퇴하라
We saw it.
All craft prepare to retreat.
장군, 이건 다시 없는 기횝니다
You won't get
another chance at this, Admiral.
We have no choice, General Calrissian.
란도 장군, 선택의 여지가 없다
저건 대적할 수 없는 화력이야
Our cruisers can't repel
firepower of that magnitude.
솔로 장군이 곧
방어망을 부술 겁니다
Han will have that shield down.
We've gotta give him more time.
갑니다
We're coming.
빨리 와
Come on.
알투, 서둘러
R2, hurry!
세상에!
My goodness!
알투, 어쩌자고 그런
무모한 짓을 하니?
Why did you have to be so brave?
연결선을 끊어버려야겠군
Well, I suppose I could
hot-wire this thing.
I'll cover you.
제가 엄호하죠
될 수 있는 대로 가까이 접근해서
정확히 조준해야 합니다
Yes, I said closer.
Move as close as you can...
and engage those Stardestroyers
at point-blank range.
너무 접근하면 오래 못 버티고
벌집이 될 텐데
At that close range, we won't last long
against those Stardestroyers.
오래 못 버티더라도 놈들을
하나라도 더 처치해야죠
We'll last longer than we will
against that Death Star...
and we might
take a few of them with us.
She's gonna blow!
폭발한다!
맞았다!
I'm hit!
꼼짝없는 패전이로구나
Your fleet is lost...
'엔도'의 친구들도 별 수 없지
and your friends on the Endor moon
will not survive.
탈출은 불가능해
There is no escape...
my young apprentice.
연합군도 네 친구들도...
The Alliance will die...
이제 다 죽게 돼
as will your friends.
옳지
Good.
네 분노가 느껴지는구나
I can feel your anger.
난 무기가 없다
너의 무기를 잡아라
I am defenseless.
Take your weapon.
증오심을 끓어올려 날 쳐라
Strike me down
with all of your hatred...
그래야 암흑 세계로의
여정이 완성될 테니
and your journey towards
the dark side will be complete.
-저것 봐
-끌어 내려
- Look!
- Get him off of there.
I think I got it.
된 것 같은데
됐다!
I got it!
공주님, 괜찮아요?
Are you all right?
-어디 봐요
-별 거 아니에요
- Let's see.
- It's not bad.
-꼼짝 마!
-깜짝이야
- Freeze!
- Oh, dear.
Don't move.
움직이지 마
사랑해
- I love you.
- I know.
알아요
Hands up.
손 들어!
Stand up.
일어서!
물러 서
Stay back.
츄이
Get down here.
She's wounded.
내려 와, 공주가 다쳤어
아니, 잠깐!
No, wait.
I got an idea.
좋은 생각이 떠올랐어
잘 하는군
Good.
Use your aggressive feelings, boy.
네 안의 증오심을 끓어올려
한줄기 폭포처럼 흐르게 하라
Let the hate flow through you.
오비완이 제대로 가르쳤구나
Obi-Wan has taught you well.
I will not fight you, Father.
싸우지 않겠어요, 아버지
방어자세를 푸는 건
어리것은 짓이야
You are unwise
to lower your defenses.
자신에게 배신 당하지 마세요
Your thoughts betray you, Father.
아버지의 내부에선 지금
선과 악이 투쟁하고 있어요
I feel the good in you, the conflict.
투쟁은 없어
There is no conflict.
전에도 지금도 아버진
절 죽일 의지가 없어요
You couldn't bring yourself
to kill me before...
and I don't believe
you'll destroy me now.
You underestimate
the power of the dark side.
넌 암흑 세계의 힘을 얕보고 있어
싸우지 않으려면
운명을 받아들여라
If you will not fight...
then you will meet your destiny.
잘 하고 있구나
Good.
조심해, 적이 몰려 온다
- Watch out. Squad at.06.
- I'm on it, Gold Leader.
자, 갑니다
정말 멋졌어
Good shot, Red Two.
솔로, 빨리 해
날 실망시키지 말아줘
We're sure in the middle of it now.
Come on, Han, old buddy.
Don't let me down.
상황은 종결되고
반란군은 숲으로 퇴각했습니다
It's over, Commander.
The rebels have been routed.
They're fleeing.
추격을 계속 하려면
지원군이 필요합니다
We need reinforcements
to continue the pursuit.
3개조를 지원해
Send three squads to help.
-뒷문을 열어라
-알겠습니다
- Open the back door.
- Sir.
Throw me another charge.
폭탄을 더 줘
영원히 숨을 순 없다, 루크
You cannot hide forever, Luke.
싸우지 않겠어요
I will not fight you.
암흑 세계로 자신을 던져라
Give yourself to the dark side.
그래야만 네 친구들을 구한다
It is the only way
you can save your friends.
마음에게 배신 당하지 않으려면
집착을 끊어라
Yes.
Your thoughts betray you.
Your feelings for them are strong...
특히...
especially for...
네 누이에게!
sister.
그러고 보니
쌍둥이 누이가 있군
So you have a twin sister.
네 마음은 벌써 그녀를 배신했다
Your feelings have now
betrayed her too.
오비완이 그 애를
내게 숨긴 건 현명했지만
Obi-Wan was wise
to hide her from me.
그는 실패했어
Now his failure is complete.
네가 암흑 세계로 안 오면...
If you will not turn
to the dark side...
그녀가 오게 된다
then perhaps she will.
안돼!
Never!
정말 잘 했어
Good!
너의 증오심이 널 강하게 했다
Your hate has made you powerful.
이제 운명에 순응하여
Now, fulfill your destiny...
아버지의 자리를 채워라
and take your father's place at my side.
싫다
Never.
난 결코 굴복하지 않는다
I'll never turn to the dark side.
You've failed, Your Highness.
황제, 당신은 실패했어
난 제다이다
여기 계신 내 아버지처럼
I am a Jedi...
Iike my father before me.
좋을 대로 해라, 제다이
So be it,Jedi.
Move! Move!
어서 피해!
방어망이 뚫렸다
죽음의 별 중심부를 공격하라
The shield is down. Commence attack
on the Death Star's main reactor.
전진하고 있습니다
모두 나를 따르라
We're on ourway. Red Group,
Gold Group, all fighters follow me.
I told you they'd do it.
뭐랬어? 해 낼 거랬잖아
내게 굴복하지 않겠다면
If you will not be turned...
you will be destroyed.
멸하는 수밖에 없지
어리석은 녀석
Young fool.
최후의 순간에야 깨닫다니
Only now, at the end...
do you understand.
그 저급한 잔재주로 어찌 감히
어둠의 세력을 대적하는가?
Your feeble skills are no match
for the power of the dark side.
너의 무지가 그 값을 치르리라
You have paid the price
for your lack of vision.
아버지, 제발
Father, please!
도와 줘요!
젊은 스카이워커여
Now, young Skywalker...
이제 그만 죽여주마
you will die.
자, 간다
I'm going in.
우리도 가자
Here goes nothing.
가장 강력한 동력장치를
목표물로 설정한다
Lock onto the strongest power source.
It should be the power generator.
전열을 정비하라
초고속으로 전진한다
Form up. Stay alert.
We could run out of space real fast.
여기서 흩어진 뒤
입구에서 다시 만나자
Split up and head back to the surface.
몇 대를 유인해서 치고 빠져라
See if you can get a few
of those TIE fighters to follow you.
알겠습니다
Copy, Gold Leader.
간 떨어질 뻔했네
That was too close.
공격의 강도를 더욱 높여라
중앙 사령부를 집중 공격한다
We've got to give
those fighters more time.
Concentrate all fire
on that Super Stardestroyer.
방어망이 통째로 뚫렸습니다
Sir, we've lost our
bridge deflector shields.
비상용 발전기를 총동원 해!
중앙을 통과시켜선 안돼!
Intensify the forward batteries.
I don't want anything to get through.
화력을 집결시켜!
Intensify forward firepower!
너무 늦었습니다
Too late!
루크, 이 마스크를 벗겨 주겠니?
Help me take this mask off.
그럼 돌아가실 거예요
But you'll die.
죽음을 막을 수 있는 건 없다
Nothing can stop that now.
Just for once...
한 번만이라도...
너를 내 눈으로
직접 보게 해다오
Iet me...
Iook on you with my own eyes.
이제...
Now go, my son.
내 아들아
날 떠나거라
Leave me.
안돼요, 함께 가요
No. You're coming with me.
I'll not leave you here.
I've got to save you.
아버지를 살리겠어요
넌 이미 날 살렸단다, 루크
You already have, Luke.
네 판단이 옳았다
You were right.
You were right about me.
네 누이에게도 그렇게 전해다오
Tell your sister...
you were right.
아버지
Father.
떠나지 않을 겁니다
I won't leave you.
저기 있다
There it is.
그렇군, 북쪽에 있는
에너지 조종탑을 향해 돌진하라
Wedge, go for the power regulator
on the north tower.
알겠습니다
Copy, Gold Leader.
I'm already on my way out.
지금 돌진 개시합니다
죽음의 별을 떠나야 할 때다
Move the fleet
away from the Death Star.
They did it!
해냈어!
루크는 무사히 떠났을 거요
I'm sure Luke wasn't
on that thing when it blew.
맞아요, 느낄 수 있어요
He wasn't.
I can feel it.
You love him.
그를 사랑하는군
Don't you?
말해 봐요
Yes.
그래요
All right. I understand.
괜찮아요, 이해해요
Fine.
그가 돌아오면 떠나주겠소
When he comes back...
I won't get in the way.
It's not like that at all.
그런게 아니에요
그는 내 동생이에요
He's my brother.
이제 우린 자유다!
Wesa free!